好 我们第一次见到了TextView的代码
Okay, so we've seen TextView code for the first time.
— 但是这看起来没什么用处
&gt;&gt; But it's kind of hanging out in limbo.
— 没错 所以我们要找个地方安置它
&gt;&gt; Right, we do need a space where we can house it.
- 是的，那个地方就是 IDE
&gt;&gt; Yeah, that space is an IDE.
- 又是一个缩写
&gt;&gt; There's that acronym again.
这是什么意思啊 Catherine?
What does it stand for again, Catherine?
- 集成开发环境
- 没错
&gt;&gt; Integrated Development Environment &gt;&gt; Right, and
我们将在课程里使用 Android Studio
we are going to be using Android Studio in this class.
这就是它的模样
This is what it looks like.
有一点吓人
Still a little intimidating.
- 嗯 我想我们要一个台阶
&gt;&gt; Yeah. I think we might need something
能让我们的听众理解得更容易一些
that will help our learner ramp up a little bit easier.
- 没错 我们一直在开发用于练习 Android Studio
&gt;&gt; Right, so we've been working on developing something that is
的一套东西 用计算机科学里正式的话描述
Android Studio on training wheels, in the tradition of really convoluted
就是 XMLV
acronyms in computer science, we are calling it XMLV.
- 它是 XML 可视化器
&gt;&gt; Which stands for XML Visualizer.
- 那么 你写过一点XML吗？
&gt;&gt; So you write a little bit of XML?
你可以看见输出
You get to see the output.
你写得更多 你就可以看见更多输出
You write some more, you get to see more output.
- 没错
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
那么我们就用一下
So let's go use it.
- 好
&gt;&gt; Okay.
- 这个XML可视化器被专门用于本课程
&gt;&gt; Since this XML visualizer was created specifically for this course,
它不会提供Android Studio的所有功能
it won't provide all the functionality that Android Studio supports.
但是在本课程的最后
But eventually in the problem set of this lesson,
我们会教给你Android Studio 所以你不会再用这个网站了
we'll get you into Android Studio so you won't need this website anymore.
在教师笔记(instructor notes)中有链接
A link is in the instructor notes If you want to follow along.
这段代码中 显示的文字是 Happy Birthday
For this code, the text says Happy Birthday.
所以看到右边的设备显示的也是 Happy Birthday
So when I look at the device it says, Happy Birthday.
现在 我们试着把文字换成 Happy Birthday, Kunal
Now let's try to change the text to Happy Birthday, Kunal.
那么我现在放大设备预览器的时候它就会显示
And then when I zoom in on the device preview you see that it now says,
Happy Birthday, Kunal
Happy Birthday, Kunal.
当试图修改宽度和高度的时候会发生什么
And what happens by trying to stand the width and the height.
我选择一些既定的数值如宽度300dp
I'll pick some arbitrary values like the 300dp for
以及高度500
the width and 500 for the height.
现在在预览区，你可以看见TextView大了一点点
And now in the preview pane, you see that the TextView is a lot bigger.
然而文字还是在左上角 保持一样的大小
The text though, however, is still the same size in the top left corner.
请注意 高度和宽度的300和500
Notice that for the width and height values of 300 and
后面都跟着单位dp
500 is followed by dp in each case.
这个单位和厘米或毫米一样
This is a unit of measure like centimeters or
可以描述Android上面view的尺寸
millimeters, that we use to describe the size of views on Android.
也可以描述view的距离
As well as the distancing between views.
单位dp全称是密度无关像素(density-independent pixels)
The unit dp stands for density-independent pixels.
让我来解释为什么需要它
Let me explain why we need that.
这些漂亮的矩形代表不同的设备
Say these beautifully drawn rectangles represent different devices.
它们大小相同 却有着不同的分辨率
They're the same physical size, but they differ in terms of resolution.
这是一个中型分辨率的设备 有着适中大小的像素
This is a medium resolution device with a medium number of pixels on the screen,
高分辨率设备 还有超高分辨率设备
high resolution and extra-high resolution device.
When I say pixel, I mean a phone screen is made up of many tiny squares,
which are pixels, and they light up based on what you're looking at.
So if I define the size of a view, for example, a button, to be 2 pixels tall
by 2 pixels wide, this is what it would look like on a medium resolution device.
On a high resolution device, it would also be 2 pixels by 2 pixels.
But it's a little bit smaller,
because there's a lot more pixels trying to be packed into this device, and
then on an extra high resolution device where there's tons more pixels packed
into this space, this button is actually pretty tiny.
I can barely tap on it with my finger.
I have to use edge of my finger or my fingernail to reach it.
Just because I have extra high resolution device,
doesn't mean I have a smaller finger.
I still want to be able to tap the buttons on the screen.
And that is why we have density-independent pixels.
I can define my button to be 2dps tall by 2dps wide.
This is what it would look like across the different devices.
It is the same physical size, but
under the hood Android is mapping it to a different number of pixels.
You don't have to worry about any of that logic, all you need to remember
is that you need to define your sizes in terms of dp values.
When designing your apps, we recommend that all touch targets like buttons
should be at least 48dps tall and wide.
Notice that it says 48dps and not 48 pixels,
otherwise it would be really tiny on this extra high resolution device.
This will make your app easy to use for everyone.
So with all of this knowledge, I want you to try and
change the TextView code now.
You're going to be writing your very first lines of XML, how exciting.
So first try to change the text in the TextView.
And then try to change the sides of the TextView.
Then I want you to try to create an error sad face.
And then I want you to undo it, happy face.